Jamaal Farahkhan

Experienced Analyst

Kansas City, MO 64124 jfarahkhan81@gmail.com 8167269682

My skills accumulated during a 20-year blended career of Intelligence Analysis and Human Services would allow me to contribute immediately to an organization. I conducted Intelligence Operations for 10-years in support of personnel operating in; Mediterranean Sea, Red Sea, Arabian Gulf, Indian Ocean, Iraq and Afghanistan. I utilized GIS system to supply maritime, aeronautical, geographical, imagery, geological updates, analysis and dissemination of information to operators. I have independently maintained a secured chart vault and publication library. I worked on a Counter-Terrorism Database, applying a multidisciplinary approach in support of deployed military units. My degree in Psychology has afforded me the flexibility to provide quality performance in varied job environments. More important, it brought a human element to my professional skills. I improved my own interpersonal skills by empathetically assisting individuals struggling with difficult life issues. While working in Human Services, I have gathered skills that translate well into a varied position. I have extensively employed statistical methods, tracked and analyzed data, drafted treatment plans and completed detail evaluations.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Curriculum Developer

CorePrepKC - Kansas City, MO March 2021 to Present

Provides educational products to homeschool families. Conducts trainings online and in person.

Targeted Case Manager

Serenity Case Management Services - Topeka, KS June 2020 to January 2021

As a Targeted Case Manager I was primarily responsible for the assessment of client functioning and the development as well as the preparation and implementation of a comprehensive Targeted Case Management Service Plan.

Behavioral Health Technician

Harbor Point Behavioral Health Center - Portsmouth, VA July 2019 to March 2020

The overall responsibility of the Mental Health Technician (MHT) is to develop a therapeutic relationship with and provide appropriate guidance and supervision to children and teenagers receiving treatment. During school hours, the MHT is the paraprofessional who manages behaviors and assists the teacher in the classroom. We are licensed by The Virginia Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services and the Virginia Department of Education. The facility specialized in treating children and adolescents with depression, bipolar, ADHD, and other mental health issues.

Special Education Paraprofessional

Sherwood Autism Center - Kansas City, MO February 2018 to June 2019

Implements and records progress of the IEP of several students. Teaches students as a class, in small groups, and one-on-one. Assists teacher in the maintenance of progress reports, student schedules and lesson plans. Uses communication systems, adaptive materials and equipment, sensory integration activities. Assists parents, teachers and other staff during drop-off and pick-up at the school.

Behavior Interventionist

FosterAdopt Connect February 2017 to February 2018

Established and implemented skills and training to youth, adolescents and families within the foster care system. Employed techniques consistent with research conducted by Bruce D. Perry on treating trauma. Utilized elements of evidenced based practices and crisis prevention to help clients avoid unacceptable behaviors. Successfully communicated the link between behaviors and consequences to clients. Taught clients de-escalation and calming techniques. Coordinated with various, members of clients treatment team to tailor treatment to fit the individual client.

Intensive In-Home Counselor- Contractor

Kaleidoscope Counseling and Casework Services/Crescent C&CS - Portsmouth, VA March 2012 to February 2017

Provided mental health services to at risk youth at their residence. Connected clients and their families to resources within the community. Coordinated with other members of the treatment team to individualize treatment plans and provide the best evidenced based practices to serve clients. Created ISPs, Quarterly Reports, BIRP Notes, Initial Assessments, Disclosure forms, Discharge forms and other forms of documentation.

Therapeutic Staff Support

Community Education Centers - Chesapeake, VA March 2013 to October 2014

Provided instruction and counseling to incarcerated adults in a medium security prison. Provided individual and group counseling to clients. Facilitated lectures and training for groups of up to 90 clients. Drafted progress notes and monthly summaries. Assisted clients with substance abuse treatment and reentry planning. Administered Addiction Severity Index (ASI) to new clients.

Therapeutic Day Treatment Counselor

Compasion LLC - Virginia Beach, VA January 2011 to March 2013

Worked with at risk youth at alternative school. Used evidenced based practices to teach clients anger management, calming techniques, communication skills and deescalation strategies. Helped clients maintain appropriate behaviors in order to complete assignments, community service and school assigned step program in order to return to their home school.

Youth Counselor

Eckerd Youth Alternatives - Clewiston, FL June 2008 to January 2011

Provided instruction and counseling to groups of 8-12 at risk youth in a wilderness setting. Taught clients the impact of natural and logical consequences, life skills and worked with treatment team to provide mental health treatment. Helped to implement treatment plans, facilitated recreational activities and assisted with educational activities.

Defense Department

U.S. Navy/Lockheed Martin - Tampa, FL June 1999 to June 2008

Provided intelligence analysis while aboard the USS John F Kennedy in support of maritime operations and strike warfare analysis. Populated counter terrorism database in support of USCENTCOM operations. Maintained classified library.

Education

BA Psychology in Psychology

Saint Leo University - Saint Leo, FL January 2007 to December 2011

Strike Warfare Analysis Course in Strike Warfare

The Navy and Marine Corps Intelligence Training Center (NMITC) - Virginia Beach, VA March 2002 to July 2002

GCCS-M in Global command and control systems

The Navy and Marine Corps Intelligence Training Center (NMITC) - Virginia Beach, VA January 2002 to February 2002

Intelligence A School in Intelligence

The Navy and Marine Corps Intelligence Training Center (NMITC) - Virginia Beach, VA June 1999 to December 1999

Skills

- Analyst Notebook (4 years)
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- CPR
- Teaching
- · Organizational Skills
- · CPR Certified
- Microsoft Excel
- training
- Powerpoint
- Mental Health
- Documentation
- Case Management
- Management

- Data Collection
- Intelligence Experience
- Individual / Group Counseling
- GIS
- Addiction Counseling
- Intelligence Analysis
- Social Work
- · Crisis Intervention
- Autism Experience
- Excel (10+ years)
- JavaScript (4 years)
- Front-End Development (1 year)
- HTML5 (10+ years)
- Mental Health Counseling
- Group Therapy
- Behavioral Therapy
- Special Education
- · Child & Family Counseling
- Applied Behavior Analysis
- CSS3 (Less than 1 year)
- · Behavioral Health
- Cognitive Behavioral Therapy
- Intake Experience
- SQL
- Relational Databases (6 years)

Military Service

Branch: Navy

Service Country: United States

Rank: E5

June 1999 to June 2003

Commendations:

Meritorious Unit Award, Good Conduct Award, Sea Service.

Certifications and Licenses

CPR & First Aid

October 2017 to October 2019

Certified

Crisis Prevention Intervention

June 2017 to June 2018

Certified

MANDT

August 2018 to August 2020

Certified

Driver's License